Register of the Stanislaw Mikolajczyk Papers, 1899-1966
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1966
  - Yugoslavia - Military war readiness, 1952 (Folder 24)
  - Zabiello, Stanislaw, "Polska a Zwiazek Sowiecki," 1938. Mimeograph (Folder 25)
  - Zaleski, August, "Historia Prezydentury Zalewskiego podlug Bregmana," 1955. Clipping (Folder 26)
  - Zawisza, Aleksander. Exposés, 1964-1965 (Folder 27)
  - Zwiazek Bojownikow o Wolnosc i Demokracje - Moczar, Mieczyslaw. Clippings, 1965 (Folder 28)
- PRINTED MATTER, 1941-1965
  - General. Scrapbooks
    - 1941-1942 (Box 167, Folder 1)
    - 1942-1943 (Folder 2)
  - Clippings
    - American press
      - 1946 - Polish elections (Box 168, Folder 1)
      - 1947 - Poland's internal conditions (Folder 2)
      - 1948
        - January-March (Folder 3)
        - April-June (Folder 4)
        - July September (Folder 5)
        - October-December (Folder 6)
      - 1949
        - January-March (Box 169, Folder 1)
        - April-September (Folder 2)
      - 1951
        - January-March (Folder 3)
        - April-June (Folder 4)
        - July-September (Box 170, Folder 1)
        - October-December (Folder 2)
      - 1952
        - January-March (Folder 3)
        - April-June (Folder 4)
        - July-September (Box 171, Folder 1)
        - October-December (Folder 2)
      - 1953
        - January (Folder 3)
        - February (Folder 4)
        - March
          - 1-7 (Box 172, Folder 1)
          - 8-17 (Folder 2)
          - 18-29 (Folder 3)
        - April
          - 1-14 (Folder 4)
          - 15-30 (Folder 5)
        - May
          - 1-15 (Box 173, Folder 1)
          - 16-29 (Folder 2)
        - June
          - 1-15 (Folder 3)
          - 16-29 (Folder 4)
        - July
          - 1-15 (Folder 5)
          - 16-31 (Box 174, Folder 1)
        - August
          - 1-15 (Folder 2)
          - 16-22 (Folder 3)
        - September
          - 1-15 (Box 175, Folder 1)
          - 16-29 (Folder 2)
        - October (Folder 3)
        - November (Folder 4)
        - December (Folder 5)
      - 1954
        - January (Box 176, Folder 1)
        - February (Folder 2)
        - March (Folder 3)
        - April (Folder 4)
        - May-June (Folder 5)
        - July (Folder 6)
        - August (Folder 7)
        - September-November (Folder 8)
      - 1955. Yalta Conference Official Record published in New York Times (Folder 9)
      - 1956 - Poznan Uprising
        - June 28-July 7 (Box 177, Folder 1)
        - July 8-25 (Folder 2)
        - August-November (Folder 3)
      - 1957
        - January (Folder 4)
        - February (Folder 5)
      - 1958 (Folder 6)
      - 1961 (Folder 7)
      - 1962
        - Cuban crisis and blockade (Folder 8)
        - Salisbury, Harrison E. on Soviet Union (Folder 9)
      - 1964 - Soviet politics (Folder 10)
      - 1965 - Polish parliamentary elections (Folder 11)
    - British press
      - 1945 (Box 178, Folder 1)
      - 1947 (Folder 2)
      - 1948 (Folder 3)
      - 1951-1952 (Folder 4)
      - 1953. Includes clippings refering to Churchill's memoirs (Folder 5)
      - 1956 - Poznan Uprising
        - June 29-30 (Folder 6)
        - July
          - 1-2 (Folder 7)
          - 3-4 (Folder 8)
          - 5-14 (Folder 9)
        - October
          - General (Box 179, Folder 1)
          - Poznan trials (Folder 2)
      - 1957 January - Polish elections (Folder 3)
      - 1958 (Folder 4)
    - French press
      - 1947 January - Polish elections (Folder 5)
      - 1948 (Folder 6)
      - 1952 (Folder 7)
      - 1956 (Folder 8)
      - 1958 (Folder 9)
      - 1962 (Folder 10)
    - German press
      - 1947 (Folder 11)
      - 1949 (Folder 12)
      - 1951-1952 (Folder 13)
      - 1957 (Folder 14)
      - 1958 (Folder 15)
      - 1965 - Yalta anniversary (Folder 16)
    - Polish press, Communist - Poland
      - 1946 - Warsaw Uprising and Underground activities (Box 180, Folder 1)
      - 1947 (Folder 2)
      - 1948
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Nowe Drogi - Plenum meeting of the Central Committee of the Polish United Workers Party, November (English translation of proceedings) (Folder 4)
      - 1949 - Communist attacks on peasant movement (Folder 5)
      - 1950 - Communist attacks on peasant movement (Folder 6)
      - 1951 - Attacks on Mikolajczyk and émigré circles (Folder 7)
      - 1952
        - January-July
          - Communist attacks on émigré circles (Folder 8)
          - Parliamentary elections (Folder 9)
        - July-December - Communist attacks on émigré circles (Box 181, Folder 1)
        - August - Parliamentary elections (Folder 2)
        - September-October
          - Communist Party of Soviet Union, XIXth Congress (Folder 3)
          - Parliamentary elections (Folder 4)
      - 1953 (Folder 5)
      - 1954 (Folder 6)
      - 1956
        - General
          - General (Folder 7)
          - Transcripts (Folder 8)
        - October-December (Folder 9)
      - 1957
        - January-February
          - General (Box 182, Folder 1)
          - List of election candidates (Folder 2)
        - January-September (Folder 3)
        - January-December (Folder 4)
        - July (Folder 5)
        - August-November (Folder 6)
      - 1958 (Folder 7)
      - 1961
        - General
          - General
            - General (Folder 8)
            - Local peasant conventions (Folder 9)
          - Elections
            - Part 1 (Box 183, Folder 1)
            - Part 2 (Folder 2)
        - Dziennik Ludowy (Folder 3)
        - Gazeta Chlopska (Folder 4)
        - Gromada (Folder 5)
        - Trybuna Ludu (Folder 6)
      - 1962
        - General (Folder 7)
        - Krajowa Agencja Informacyjna: Biuletyn (Folder 8)
      - 1964 - Zjednoczone Stronnictwo Ludowe
        - General (Folder 9)
        - Dziennik Ludowy (Folder 10)
        - Trybuna Ludu (Folder 11)
        - Zielony Sztandar (Folder 12)
      - 1965 - Parliamentary elections
        - March (Folder 13)
        - April (Folder 14)
        - May (Box 184, Folder 1)
        - June
          - General (Folder 2)
          - Profiles of elected parliament members (Folder 3)
    - Polish press, Émigré
      - General
        - 1941-1942. Orzel Bialy: Polska Walczaca na Wschodzie (Folder 4)
        - 1946 (Folder 5)
        - 1948 (Folder 6)
        - 1949
          - May-June (Folder 7)
          - July (Box 185, Folder 1)
          - August (Folder 2)
          - October-September (Folder 3)
          - November-December (Folder 4)
        - 1950
          - January-February (Folder 5)
          - March-May (Box 186, Folder 1)
          - June (Folder 2)
        - 1951 (Folder 3)
        - 1952
          - January-February (Folder 4)
          - March-December (Folder 5)
        - 1954
          - January-February (Box 187, Folder 1)
          - March-December (Folder 2)
        - 1955
          - February (Folder 3)
          - March - Polish Peasant Party Congress
            - General (Folder 4)
            - Narodowiec
              - Part 1 (Folder 5)
              - Part 2 (Folder 6)
              - Part 3 (Folder 7)
            - Pro-Communist press (Box 188, Folder 1)
          - April-July (Folder 2)
          - August-December (Folder 3)
        - 1956 - Poznan Uprising
          - April (Folder 4)
          - June 29 - July 5 (Folder 5)
          - July
            - 5-7 (Folder 6)
            - 8-11 (Box 189, Folder 1)
            - 12-13 (Folder 2)
            - 14-16 (Folder 3)
            - 17-18 (Folder 4)
            - 19-30 (Folder 5)
          - August-September (Folder 6)
          - October (Folder 7)
        - 1957 (Box 190)
          - January-February (Folder 1)
          - March-April (Folder 2)
          - May-June (Folder 3)
          - July-December (Folder 4)
        - 1958 (Folder 5)
        - 1960 April-June (Folder 6)
        - 1962 (Folder 7)
        - 1963 (Folder 8)
        - 1964 - Anniversary of Warsaw Uprising (Folder 9)
      - Polish-American press
        - General
          - 1941, Sikorski and Mikolajczyk trips
            - March (Box 191, Folder 1)
            - April
              - 1-24 (Folder 2)
              - 25-30 (Folder 3)
            - May
              - General (Folder 4)
              - 1-4 (Folder 5)
              - 5-9 (Folder 6)
              - 10-12 (Folder 7)
            - June (Folder 8)
            - July (Folder 9)
          - 1947
            - October (Folder 10)
            - November
              - 1-10 (Folder 11)
              - 11-20 (Folder 12)
              - 21-30 (Folder 13)
            - December
              - 1-10 (Box 192, Folder 1)
              - 11-20 (Folder 2)
              - 21-31 (Folder 3)
          - 1948
            - January
              - General. "Widmo terroru," Nowy Swiat (Folder 4)
              - 1-10 (Folder 5)
              - 11-20 (Folder 6)
              - 21-31 (Box 193, Folder 1)
            - February
              - General (Folder 2)
              - "Widmo terroru," Nowy Swiat (Folder 3)
            - October-December (Folder 4)
          - 1951
            - January-March (Folder 5)
            - April-June (Folder 6)
            - July-September (Box 194, Folder 1)
            - October-December (Folder 2)
          - 1952
            - January-March (Folder 3)
            - April-June (Folder 4)
            - July-September (Folder 5)
            - October-December (Box 195, Folder 1)
          - 1953
            - January-March (Folder 2)
            - April-June (Folder 3)
            - July-September (Folder 4)
            - October-December (Box 196, Folder 1)
          - 1961 (Folder 2)
          - 1965
            - March-June - Parliamentary elections (Folder 3)
            - June - Election results (Folder 4)
        - Zjednoczona Prasa Polska w Ameryce, 1948
          - January-February (Folder 5)
          - March-April (Folder 6)
          - May-June (Folder 7)
          - July-August (Folder 8)
          - September-October (Folder 9)
          - November-December (Folder 10)
      - Polish-British
        - General
          - General
            - 1944 (Box 197, Folder 1)
            - 1948 August-December (Folder 2)
            - 1949
              - July-August (Folder 3)
              - September (Folder 4)
              - September-October (Folder 5)
              - November-December (Folder 6)
          - Biuletyn Krajowy Rady Politycznej
            - 1951 (Box 198, Folder 1)
            - 1952
              - 1-6 (Folder 2)
              - 7-12 (Folder 3)
            - 1953 (Folder 4)
          - Biuletyn Polityczny Rady Politycznej
            - 1951
              - 1-10 (Folder 5)
              - 11-20 (Folder 6)
            - 1952
              - 22-30 (Folder 7)
              - 31-43 (Folder 8)
            - 1953 (Folder 9)
        - Porozumienie Stronnictw Demokratycznych
          - 1948
            - General. List of articles (Box 199, Folder 1)
            - November-December (Folder 2)
          - 1949
            - General. Lists of articles (Folder 3)
            - January-April (Folder 4)
            - May-June (Folder 5)
            - July (Folder 6)
            - August-September (Folder 7)
            - October-December (Folder 8)
          - 1950
            - General. Lists of articles (Box 200, Folder 1)
            - January-February (Folder 2)
            - March-May (Folder 3)
            - June-August (Folder 4)
            - August-November
              - General (Folder 5)
              - Anders, Wladyslaw - Trip to the United States (Folder 6)
            - November-December (Folder 7)
          - 1951
            - General. List for August-December (Box 201, Folder 1)
            - January-February (Folder 2)
            - March-June (Folder 3)
            - August-October (Folder 4)
            - November-December (Folder 5)
          - 1952
            - List for January-August (Folder 6)
            - January-April (Folder 7)
            - May-August (Folder 8)
            - September-December (Box 202, Folder 1)
          - 1953
            - January-March (Folder 2)
            - April-June (Folder 3)
            - June-August (Folder 4)
            - August-December (Folder 5)
          - 1954
            - January-March (Folder 6)
            - April-June (Folder 7)
            - June-September (Folder 8)
      - Polish-French press
        - 1948-1950 - ZUPRO (Folder 9)
        - 1948-1952 - Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe (Folder 10)
      - Polish-German press, 1948 May (Folder 11)
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1936-1966
  - Film (Box 203)
    - Seventeen still movie film strips with images of Polish cities and Polish history
    - Motion picture film, "Inaugural Meeting of the Polish National Council (Rada Narodowa) at the Polish Embassy in Paris, January 23, 1940." One reel of 16 mm, black and white, with sound track, 564 feet (Box 204)
  - Phonorecords - Town Hall program with Mikolajczyk, "Behind the Iron Curtain," City of New York Municipal Broadcasting System WNYC, 1949 November 16 (Box 205, Folder 1-5)
  - Phonotape cassettes
    - "Czesc artystyczna 'Wici', 1960: Przemowienie Pana Prezesa po wyborze" (Box 206, Folder 1)
    - "Highlights from the World Congress of the Polish Peasant Party (PSL), December 15, 1959: Exerpts from Mikolajczyk Exposé I" (Folder 2)
    - "Highlights from the World Congress of the Polish Peasant Party (PSL), December 15, 1959: Exerpts from Mikolajczyk Exposé II" (Folder 3)
    - "Highlights from the World Congress of the Polish Peasant Party (PSL), December 15, 1959: Telegrams" (Folder 4)
    - "Highlights from the World Congress of the Polish Peasant Party (PSL), December 15, 1959: Wici" (Folder 5)
    - "International Peasant Union Congress, 1956: Mikolajczyk's Speeches" (Folder 6)
    - "Opinion in the Capital, January 5, 8 PM, channel 5, WNEW-TV, Stanislaw Mikolajczyk, conducted by Mark Evans, Mrs. Margueritte Higgings, Guest Report," n.d. (Folder 7)
    - "Program Na Swieto Ludowe w 1952 roku z udzialem prezesa Stanislawa Mikolajczyka, dr. Dimitrow (nie jest na tasmie) Banczyk, Wojcik, Raczkowski, Raczkowska, Zaleski, Paul" (Folder 8)
    - "Przemowienie na Swiecie Ludowym, 8 czerwca 1952"
      - Tape 1 (Folder 9)
      - Tape 2 (Folder 10)
    - "Przemowienie Prezesa Mikolajczyka wygloszone w Brukseli w 1958 r." (Folder 11)
    - "Tape I: Od zagajenia do przemowienia Pana Cernego, ktore zaczyna sie od 590 a konczy sie na 899 na naszym aparacie. Sprawozdanie ze spotkania z Sikorskim 'and this meeting'" (Folder 12)
    - "Tape II: Zaczyna sie od koncowej czesci przemowienia Pana Cernego a konczy sie na pierwszej czesci przemowienia Prezesa Mikolajczyka z zapowiedzia co Witos powiedzial w procesie brzeskim" (Folder 13)
    - "Tape III: Zakonczenie. Czesc III" (Folder 14)
    - "Tasma z przemowieniem Prezesa Stanislawa Mikolajczyka w 10-ta rocznice smierci Wincentego Witosa. Od poczatku no nr. 66 przemowienie w dniu pogrzebu z New Yorku. Od nr. 70 do 245 przemowienie w 10-ta rocznice smierci. Dalsza czesc nagranie ponowne- powtorzenie w tej samej kolejnosci" (Folder 15)
    - Unidentified tape (Folder 16)
  - Phonotapes
    - "Kongres International Peasant Union. Pierwszy dzien kongresu, 30 maja, 1959"
      - Tasma nr. 1. Zaczecie Kongresu (Box 207, Folder 1)
      - Tasma nr. 2 (Folder 2)
      - Tasma nr. 3 (Folder 3)
      - Tasma nr. 5 (Folder 4)
      - Tasma nr. 6. Przemowienie Prezesa Mikolajczyka, ciag dalszy na tasmie 7 (Folder 5)
      - Tasma nr. 7 (Folder 6)
      - Tasma nr. 8. Dalszy ciag przemowienia Prezesa Mikolajczyka z tasmy no. 7. Madovisga (?), Gothard (Folder 7)
      - Tasma nr. 9. Gothard, Szymczak (Folder 8)
      - Tasma no. 10 (Folder 9)
    - "Kongres International Peasant Union. Rozpoczecie kongresu w dniu 30 maja 1959, Washington DC"
      - Tasma nr. 1 (Folder 10)
      - Tasma nr. 2 (Folder 11)
      - Tasma nr. 3 (Folder 12)
      - Tasma nr. 4. Popoludniowa sesja kongresu w dniu 30 maja 1959, Washington, D.C. (Folder 13)
      - Tasma nr. 5. Przemowienie Prezesa Mikolajczyka (Folder 14)
      - Tasma nr. 6. Ciag dalszy przemowienia Prezesa Mikolajczyka z tasmy nr. 5 (Folder 15)
      - Tasma nr. 7. Przemowienie Mr. ?, Bosiaga, Madariaga? (Folder 16)
      - Tasma nr. 8. Zakonczenie przemowienia Mr. Madariaga I przemowienie Mr. Genthardt (Gothard?) (Folder 17)
      - Tasma nr. 9. Przemowienie Mr. Letrich I przemowienie P. Mikolajczyka (Folder 18)
      - Tasma nr. 10. Drudi dzien Kongresu IPN, Washington, D.C. Zakonczenie (Folder 19)
    - "Kongres Francuski PSL, 12 pazdziernika 1963"
      - Tasma 1 (Folder 20)
      - Tasma 2 (Folder 21)
      - Tasma 3 (Folder 22)
      - Tasma 4. Otwarcie Kongresu. Przemowienia Profesora Kota, Bitonskiego, Generala Bilotte, Palewskiego (Folder 23)
      - Tasma 5. Przemowienie gosci: Jean de Lipkowski, Auer, Bunza, Burev, Hodza, Ermeni (Folder 24)
    - "Kongres International Peasant Union. Drugi dzien kongresu, 31 maja, 1959"
      - Tasma nr. 1 (Folder 25)
      - Tasma nr. 2 (Folder 26)
      - Tasma nr. 3 (Folder 27)
      - Tasma nr. 3 (Folder 28)
      - Tasma nr. 4 (Folder 29)
      - Tasma nr. 4 (Folder 30)
      - Tasma nr. 5 (Folder 31)
      - Tasma nr. 6 (Folder 32)
    - "Mikolajczyk's Speech, Probably 1947" (Folder 33)
    - "Notatki do pamietnika. Spisane"
      - Tasma nr. 1 (Folder 34)
      - Tasma Nr. 2 (Folder 35)
      - Tasma nr. 3 (Folder 36)
    - "Pogrzeb sp. Prezesa Stanislawa Mikolajczyka. Nagrania RFE z Waszyngtonu 17 grudnia 1966. Tasma nr. 1. A. Kazanie Ks. Pralata Bela Varga w kosciele Chrystusa Krola" (Folder 37)
    - "Pogrzeb sp. Prezesa Stanislawa Mikolajczyka. Nagrania RFE z Waszyngtonu 17 grudnia 1966. Tasma nr. 2. B. Przemowienia na cemntarzu: 1. Boleslaw Bilogan, 2. Karol Burke, 3. Ferencz Nagy, 4. Richard Flanagan, 5. Dr. G. Dymitrow" (Folder 38)
    - "Pogrzeb sp. Prezesa Stanislawa Mikolajczyka. Nagrania RFE z Waszyngtonu 17 grudnia 1966. Tasma nr. 3. B. Przemowienia na cemntarzu: C. Przemowienia na cmentarzu: 6. Dr. Jurczynski, 7. Zofia Grzelakowa, 8. Andrzej Pomian, 9. Stanislaw Mostwin, 10. Stanislaw Banczyk, 11. Boleslaw Krakowski, 12. Tadeusz Paul" (Folder 39)
    - "Polish Peasant Chicago. Rehearsed copy," n.d. (Folder 40)
    - "Przemowienie Prezesa Mikolajczyka na telewizji po smierci Imre Nagy," n.d. (Folder 41)
    - "Swiatowy Kongres PSL, 13 pazdziernika 1963"
      - Tasma nr. 3 (Folder 42)
      - Tasma nr. 10. Profesor Kot (Folder 43)
      - Tasma nr. 11. Profesor Kot (Folder 44)
      - Tasma nr. 13 (Folder 45)
    - "Wici" slubowanie, przemowienie Prezesa Mikolajczyka, spiew artysty," n.d. (Folder 46)
    - "Wywiad P. Higgings i P. Evans z Prezesem Mikolajczykiem na telewizji 5 stycznia 1964. Tasma I" (Folder 47)
    - "Wywiad P. Higgings i P. Evans z Prezesem Mikolajczykiem na telewizji 5 stycznia 1964. Tasma II" (Folder 48)
    - Miscellany
      - "Od zagajenia do przemowienia Pana Cernego, ktore zaczyna sie od 590 a konczy na 899 na naszym aparacie. Sprawozdanie ze spotkania z Sikorskim 'and this meeting'" (Box 208, Folder 1)
      - "Zaczyna sie druga czesc przemowienia Pana Cernego, konczy sie w trakcie przemowienia Prezesa Mikolajczyka na strinie 17 tekstu 'our most important task is to normalize'" (Folder 2)
      - "Part 3" (Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 1936-1963
    - 13 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk (studio portraits), ca. 1940s and 1950s (Box 209, Folder 1)
    - 2 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk's trip to Ireland and inspection of Polish Parachute Brigade, 1941-1943 (Folder 2)
    - 1 print depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk's government members and editorial staff of Dziennik Polski, October 1943 (Folder 3)
    - 4 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during medal award ceremony, 1944? (Folder 4)
    - 12 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk and his delegation at British airport before their departure for Moscow, 1944 (Folder 5)
    - 26 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during his trip to Moscow on a Middle Eastern stop-over, 1944 (Folder 6)
    - 1 print depicting Stanislaw Milolajczyk and Franklin D. Roosevelt in the Oval Office, 1944 (Folder 7)
    - 19 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during welcoming demonstrations in Katowice, Poland, 1946 (Folder 8)
    - 6 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk and other government members at a meeting in London, 1947 (Folder 9)
    - 6 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk at the airport in New York after his arrival in the United States, 1947 (Folder 10)
    - 4 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during his trip to the United States, 1947 (Folder 11)
    - 6 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during his visit at Fairleigh Dickinson Junior College, 1947 December (Folder 12)
    - 19 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during his trips in 1948 (Folder 13)
    - 5 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during his stay in Chicago, 1948 (Folder 14)
    - 4 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during his visit of Zwiazek Narodowy Polski in Chicago, 1948 (Folder 15)
    - 5 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during his visit to Hartford, Connecticut, 1948 (Folder 16)
    - 3 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during his visit at the United Nations, New York, 1948 or 1957? (Folder 17)
    - 1 print depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during his visit to the Vatican, 1948 (Folder 18)
    - 2 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during his trip to Germany, 1948 (Folder 19)
    - 3 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during his trip to Toronto, Canada, 1948 (Folder 20)
    - 1 print depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk (studio portrait), 1951 (Folder 21)
    - 2 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during the East-Central European Conference, London, 1952 (Folder 22)
    - 1 print depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk at a ceremony for Wladyslaw Sikorski's death anniversary, 1953? (Folder 23)
    - 1 print depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk during the anniversary observance of the Poznan Uprising, Boston, 1958 (Folder 24)
    - 4 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk in New York harbor before his departure for Europe, 1962 (Folder 25)
    - 29 prints depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk and his entourage during their trip to Japan, 1955 (Folder 26)
    - 228 prints of Stanislaw Mikolajczyk and his entourage during their trip to Japan, 1955 (Folder 27)
    - 1 print depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk speaking at Peasant Holiday, 1960s (Folder 28)
    - 1 print depicting Stanislaw Mikolajczyk in his Washington office, 1963 (Folder 29)
    - 3 prints depicting Wladyslaw Anders at Manchester Soldier's Day Observance, 1950 (Folder 30)
    - 1 print depicting Wladyslaw Banaczyk, n.d. (Folder 31)
    - 1 print depicting Mr. Celt-Chciuk, 1963 (Folder 32)
    - 1 print depicting Cardinal August Hlond, n.d. (Folder 33)
    - 1 print depicting Pope John XXIII and Cardinal Stefan Wyszynski, n.d. (Folder 34)
    - 1 print depicting John F. Kennedy during the observance of the 350th anniversary of the Poles' arrival in Jamestown, 1958 June (Folder 35)
    - 11 prints depicting Stanislaw Kot, n.d. (Folder 36)
    - 1 print depicting Mrs. Modelska in her Washington office, 1963 (Folder 37)
    - 1 print depicting General Kukiel at a tribute to General Wladyslaw Sikorski, 1944 (Folder 38)
    - 3 prints depicting the funeral of Ernst Laur, 1964 (Folder 39)
    - 2 prints depicting Metropolitan Miron during his trip to Warsaw in the 1930s (Folder 40)
    - 1 print depicting Ignacy Paderewski, Stanislaw Mikolajczyk, and Wladyslaw Sikorski, 1941 (Folder 41)
    - 3 prints depicting Alfred Poninski during diplomatic ceremonies in Bucarest, 1930s (Folder 42)
    - 2 prints depicting Wladyslaw Raczkiewicz at the medal decoration ceremony of William Laurie, 1944 (Folder 43)
    - 4 prints depicting Professor Reith at the ceremony awarding him with the Golden Cross of Merit, n.d. (Folder 44)
    - 1 print depicting Adam Romer, 1944 (Folder 45)